

Soubia Kulsum

🕿 soubiakulsum@gmail.com 📞 8073374136 👂 Bangalore 📊 Linkedin 🔗 Portfolio

PROFILE

An aspiring Product manager with over 2.5 years' of experience as an Android Developer. A collaborative product and tech enthusiast driven to innovate and enhance user experiences, cracking the case of user pain points to build solutions that make a real business impact.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Android Developer

Awign

11/2022 - 10/2023 Bangalore, India

08/2021 - 11/2022

Bangalore, India

- Lead the revamp of onboarding process for the Awign app, intervening it with the implementation of whatsapp login.
- This strategic implementation not only streamlined the user onboarding experience but also resulted in 10% surge in users completing the onboarding process. Led a teamwork effort and used data insights to cut dropout rates by 20%, making users happier and more likely to stick and continue with the app.
- Worked closely with the product team to **incorporate events** throughout the app and spearheaded AB testing initiatives, based on user feedback and data analysis.
- Optimized app performance through strategic code improvements, resulting in a 50% reduction in app crashes and a 30% increase in loading speed.

Android Developer

Saveo Healthtech Private Ltd

Clinn

- Led the swift development of a feature-rich app with a Firebase chat system, onboarded 30 doctors within 1 month.
- As a core team member, actively collaborated across departments to make decisions on essential features, while regularly interfacing with doctors to gather valuable feedback for ongoing product improvements.
- Played a key role in crafting a user-centric platform, fostering improved doctorpatient engagement and information exchange.

- Led a comprehensive restructuring of the cart logic and flow, resulting in a streamlined and more user-friendly shopping experience. This initiative contributed to a 30% increase in completed transactions.
- Implemented deeplinks integration to optimize user navigation and increase user engagement, resulting in a 15% improvement in user retention.

KEY SKILLS

PRODUCT SKILLS

Jira | Confluence | Miro | Figma | Clevertap | Mixpanel | Postman | Notion

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Kotlin | Core Java | Git | Firebase | Databases and APIs | Android Studio IDE | Android | SQL

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering

08/2016 - 07/2020 Bangalore, India

Sir M Visveswaraya Institute Of Technology